mhe-krg.org 2015-12-18

# Privacy Statement | Ministry of Higher Education

The Ministry of Higher Education & Scientific Research in Kuristan region (referred to in this document as ‘MHE’) is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This MHE Privacy Statement applies to MHE websites ([www.mhe-krg.org](http://www.mhe-krg.org/ "www.mhe-krg.org")) and governs data collection and usage at all MHE sites and services worldwide. By using MHE websites, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

This privacy statement applies to all MHE sites and services. Please read the complete MHE Privacy Statement below.  
  **  
Collection of your personal information**

At some sites, MHE collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. At other sites, MHE collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you. Some sites collect a combination of the two types of information. Information collected at one of MHE’s websites may be shared within MHE as a whole including MHE’s  family of websites. Personal and demographic data may be stored and processed outside your country (if outside the United Kingdom) and by using MHE’s website, you consent to any such transfers being made outside your country.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by MHE and may be shared with other websites within MHE’s  family of websites. This information can include your IP address, browser type, domain name, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by MHE for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of service and to provide general statistics regarding use of MHE websites.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through MHE’s website, you are encouraged to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from MHE’s website so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. The MHE is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of MHE and MHE’s family of websites.

**Use of your personal information**

The MHE’s websites collect and use your personal information to operate MHE websites and deliver the services  that you have requested. The MHE may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

**Use of cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of information sent by an organisation to your computer and stored on your hard drive to allow that organisation to recognise the user when you next visit.

The MHE’s websites may use cookies to help you personalise your online experience. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer.  They are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of a cookie is to provide a convenience feature to save you time and to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalise MHE pages, a cookie helps MHE to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, delivery addresses, and so on. When you return to the same MHE website, the information that you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use MHE features that you customised.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of MHE websites you visit.

If you wish to find out more about cookies, or wish to find out how to refuse cookes for your browser please visit aboutcookies.org which provides this information and further guidance on cookie laws.

**Security of your personal information**

The MHE secures your personal information from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. The MHE secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. When personal information (including credit card number) is transmitted, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

We also take appropriate measures to ensure that the information disclosed to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used.

**Disclosure of information we collect to outside parties**

We may pass your information to our service providers, agents and associated organisations, and, if you have consented, to other organisations who may support our objectives.

The MHE does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. The MHE may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to MHE and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

The MHE does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race or religion, without your explicit consent.

The MHE keeps track of the websites and pages that our customers visit within MHE, in order to determine what MHE sites and services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customised content within MHE to customers whose browsing behaviour indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

The MHE will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on MHE or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of MHE and its group of websites and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of MHE, its websites, or the public.

We may also need to disclose your information if required to do so by law.  
**  
Your consent**

By providing us with your personal data, including sensitive personal data such as on your health, you consent to the collection and use of any information you provide in accordance with the above purposes and this privacy statement.

You also consent to our transferring your information to countries or jurisdictions which do not provide the same level of data protection as the UK, if necessary for the above purposes. If we do make such a transfer, we will, if appropriate, put a contract in place to ensure your information is protected.

**Changes to this statement**

The MHE reserves the right to amend this privacy statement and will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect customer feedback. The MHE encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how MHE is protecting your information.

If we do so, we will post notice of the change on our website and you will be deemed to have accepted such changes.

**Contact information**

The MHE welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Statement. If you believe that MHE has not adhered to this Statement, please contact MHE by e-mail. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
